<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE preface [
<!-- Some useful entities borrowed from HTML -->
<!ENTITY ndash  "&#x2013;">
<!ENTITY mdash  "&#x2014;">
<!ENTITY hellip "&#x2026;">
<!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;">
<!-- Useful for describing APIs -->
<!ENTITY GET    '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">GET</command>'>
<!ENTITY PUT    '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">PUT</command>'>
<!ENTITY POST   '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">POST</command>'>
<!ENTITY DELETE '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">DELETE</command>'>

<!ENTITY CHECK  '<inlinemediaobject xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="img/Check_mark_23x20_02.svg"
format="SVG" scale="60"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>'>

<!ENTITY ARROW  '<inlinemediaobject xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="img/Arrow_east.svg"
format="SVG" scale="60"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>'>
]>
<preface xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="ch_object-storage-dev-overview">
    <title>Preface</title>
    <para>OpenStack Object Storage is an affordable, redundant,
        scalable, and dynamic storage service offering. The core
        storage system is designed to provide a safe, secure,
        automatically re-sizing and network-accessible way to store
        data. You can store an unlimited quantity of files and each
        file can be as large as 5&nbsp;GB, plus with large object
        creation, you can upload and store objects of virtually any
        size.</para>
    <para>OpenStack Object Storage enables you to store and get files
        and content through the Representational State Transfer (REST)
        interface. There are also language-specific APIs that utilize
        the RESTful API but make it much easier for developers to
        integrate into their applications.</para>
    <para>For more details about the OpenStack Object Storage service,
        see <link
            xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/swift/"
            >http://docs.openstack.org/developer/swift/</link>.</para>
    <para>We welcome feedback, comments, and bug reports at <link
            xlink:href="http://bugs.launchpad.net/swift"
            >http://bugs.launchpad.net/swift</link>.</para>
    <section xml:id="intended-audience-object-dev-guide">
        <title>Intended Audience</title>
        <para>This guide is intended to assist software developers who
            want to develop applications using the OpenStack Object
            Storage API. It fully documents the REST application
            programming interface (API) that allows developers to
            interact with the storage components of the OpenStack
            Object Storage system. To use the information provided
            here, you should first have a general understanding of the
            OpenStack Object Storage service and have access to an
            installation of OpenStack Object Storage. You should also
            be familiar with:</para>
        <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
            <listitem>
                <para>RESTful web services</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>HTTP/1.1 - the Swift API is HTTP 1.1, which means that you can use cache
                    control headers such as If-Modified-Since in your queries.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>You can also find language-specific APIs in several
            popular programming languages such as C#/.NET, Java, PHP,
            Python, and Ruby. These APIs utilize the REST API and are
            provided to help developers rapidly integrate OpenStack
            Object Storage support into their applications without
            needing to write at the REST interface. Each API includes
            its own documentation in its native format. For example,
            the Java API includes Javadoc documentation.</para>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="section_object-api-dochistory.xml"/>
</preface>
