<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
<!-- Some useful entities borrowed from HTML -->
<!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;">
<!-- Useful for describing APIs -->
<!ENTITY PUT '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">PUT</command>'>
<!ENTITY GET '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">GET</command>'>
<!ENTITY POST '<command xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">POST</command>'>
]>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="object_storage_api_overview">
    <title>Object Storage API overview</title>
    <para>OpenStack Object Storage is an object-based storage system
        that stores content and metadata as objects. You create,
        modify, and get objects and metadata by using the Object
        Storage API, which is implemented as a set of Representational
        State Transfer (REST) web services.</para>
    <para>For an introduction to OpenStack Object Storage, see <link
            xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/admin-guide-cloud/content/ch_admin-openstack-object-storage.html"
            >Object Storage</link> in the <citetitle>OpenStack Cloud
            Administrator Guide</citetitle>.</para>
    <para>You use the HTTPS (SSL) protocol to interact with Object
        Storage, and you use standard HTTP calls to perform API
        operations. You can also use language-specific APIs, which use
        the RESTful API, that make it easier for you to integrate into
        your applications.</para>
    <para>To assert your right to access and change data in an
        account, you identify yourself to Object Storage by using an
        authentication token. To get a token, you present your
        credentials to an authentication service. The authentication
        service returns a token and the URL for the account. Depending
        on which authentication service that you use, the URL for the
        account appears in:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">OpenStack Identity
                    Service</emphasis>. The URL is defined in the
                service catalog.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Tempauth</emphasis>. The URL
                is provided in the <literal>X-Storage-Url</literal>
                response header.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In both cases, the URL is the full URL and includes the
        account resource. For information about authentication, see
            <xref linkend="authentication"/>.</para>
    <para>The Object Storage API supports the standard, non-serialized
        response format, which is the default, and both JSON and XML
        serialized response formats. See <xref
            linkend="serialized-response-formats"/>.</para>
    <para>The Object Storage system organizes data in a hierarchy, as
        follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Account</emphasis>. Represents
                the top-level of the hierarchy.</para>
            <para>Your service provider creates your account and you
                own all resources in that account. The account defines
                a namespace for containers. A container might have the
                same name in two different accounts.</para>
            <para>In the OpenStack environment,
                    <firstterm>account</firstterm> is synonymous with
                a project or tenant.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Container</emphasis>. Defines
                a namespace for objects. An object with the same name
                in two different containers represents two different
                objects. You can create any number of containers
                within an account.</para>
            <para>In addition to containing objects, you can also use
                the container to control access to objects by using an
                access control list (ACL). You cannot store an ACL
                with individual objects.</para>
            <para>In addition, you configure and control many other
                features, such as object versioning, at the container
                level. See <xref linkend="set-object-versions"
                />.</para>
            <para>You can bulk-delete up to 10,000 containers in a
                single request. See <xref linkend="bulk-delete"
                />.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Object</emphasis>. Stores data
                content, such as documents, images, and so on. You can
                also store custom metadata with an object.</para>
            <para>With the Object Storage API, you can:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Store an unlimited number of objects. Each
                        object can be as large as 5&nbsp;GB, which is the
                        default. You can configure the maximum object
                        size.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Upload and store objects of any size with
                        large object creation. See <xref
                            linkend="large-object-creation"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Use cross-origin resource sharing to manage
                        object security. See <xref
                            linkend="cors-headers"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Compress files. See <xref
                            linkend="file-compression"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Override browser behavior for an object. See
                            <xref linkend="content-disposition"
                        />.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Schedule objects for deletion. See <xref
                            linkend="expire-objects"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Bulk-delete up to 10,000 objects in a single
                        request. See <xref linkend="bulk-delete"
                        />.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Auto-extract archive files. See <xref
                            linkend="archive-auto-extract"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Generate a URL that provides time-limited
                        &GET; access to an object. See <xref
                            linkend="tempurl"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Upload objects directly to the Object
                        Storage system from a browser by using form
                        &POST; middleware. See <xref
                            linkend="form-post"/>.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The account, container, and object hierarchy affects the way
        you interact with the Object Storage API.</para>
    <para>Specifically, the resource path reflects this structure and
        has this format:</para>
    <programlisting>/v1/{account}/{container}/{object}</programlisting>
    <para>For example, for the <literal>flowers/rose.jpg</literal>
        object in the <literal>images</literal> container in the
            <literal>12345678912345</literal> account, the resource
        path is:</para>
    <programlisting>/v1/12345678912345/images/flowers/rose.jpg</programlisting>
    <para>Notice that the object name contains the
            <literal>/</literal> character. This slash does not
        indicate that Object Storage has a sub-hierarchy called
            <literal>flowers</literal> because containers do not store
        objects in actual sub-folders. However, the inclusion of
            <literal>/</literal> or a similar convention inside object
        names enables you to create pseudo-hierarchical folders and
        directories. See <xref
            linkend="pseudo-hierarchical-folders-directories"
        />.</para>
    <para>For example, if the endpoint for Object Storage is
            <literal>objects.mycloud.com</literal>, the returned URL
        is
            <literal>https://objects.mycloud.com/v1/12345678912345</literal>.</para>
    <para>To access a container, append the container name to the
        resource path.</para>
    <para>To access an object, append the container and the object
        name to the path.</para>
    <para>If you have a large number of containers or objects, you can
        use query parameters to page through large lists of
        containers or objects. Use the <parameter>marker</parameter>,
            <parameter>limit</parameter>, and
            <parameter>end_marker</parameter> query parameters to
        control how many items are returned in a list and where the
        list starts or ends. See <xref linkend="large-lists"/>.</para>
    <para>Object Storage HTTP requests have the following default
        constraints. Your service provider might use different default
        values.</para>
    <informaltable rules="all">
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th>Item</th>
                <th>Maximum value</th>
                <th>Notes</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td>Number of HTTP headers</td>
                <td>90</td>
                <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Length of HTTP headers</td>
                <td>4096&nbsp;bytes</td>
                <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Length per HTTP request line</td>
                <td>8192&nbsp;bytes</td>
                <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Length of HTTP request</td>
                <td>5&nbsp;GB</td>
                <td/>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Length of container names</td>
                <td>256&nbsp;bytes</td>
                <td>Cannot contain the <literal>/</literal>
                    character.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Length of object names</td>
                <td>1024&nbsp;bytes</td>
                <td>By default, there are no character
                    restrictions.</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </informaltable>
    <para>You must UTF-8-encode and then URL-encode container and
        object names before you call the API binding. If you use an
        API binding that performs the URL-encoding for you, do not
        URL-encode the names before you call the API binding.
        Otherwise, you double-encode these names. Check the length
        restrictions against the URL-encoded string.</para>
    <para>These sections describe the operations that you can perform
        with the Object Storage API:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="storage_account_services"/>. Use to
                perform account-level tasks.</para>
            <para>Lists containers for a specified account. Creates,
                updates, and deletes account metadata. Shows account
                metadata.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="storage_container_services"/>. Use to
                perform container-level tasks.</para>
            <para>Lists objects in a specified container. Creates,
                shows details for, and deletes containers. Creates,
                updates, shows, and deletes container metadata.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="storage_object_services"/>. Use to
                perform object-level tasks.</para>
            <para>Creates, replaces, shows details for, and deletes
                objects. Copies objects with another object with a new
                or different name. Updates object metadata.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</section>
